opinionlab.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy | Verint Systems

### **LAST UPDATED:** **April 2019**

Verint® Systems Inc. and its Affiliates, (collectively, “Verint”) are concerned about privacy issues and want you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose information. Affiliates as used herein is defined as any entity which now or in the future controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with Verint Systems Inc., with “control” defined as the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of such person or entity, whether through the ownership of voting securities, by contract, or otherwise). A list of Affiliates can be viewed [here](https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1166388/000116638819000013/vrnt-ex211_20190131xform10.htm) .

Verint Systems Inc.’s Affiliate, Verint Americas Inc., has assumed control of ForeSee, now “Verint ForeSee”.  If you a customer of Verint ForeSee, please see the applicable privacy policy for the VerintForeSee business [here](https://www.foresee.com/privacy-policy/).

This Privacy Policy describes our practices in connection with information that we collect through the website owned and controlled by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “Site”), as well as certain information we collect from offline sources, as explained in more detail below. By providing Personal Information to us, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

If you apply for a job through the Site, our use of the Personal Information you provide through our Career Center is governed by a separate privacy policy, not this Privacy Policy. Please click <https://www.verint.com/careers/> to review our privacy policy for job seekers who apply for jobs through the Site.

Verint seeks to comply with all laws applicable to it when collecting, using or disclosing information.

## **Personal Information**

### **Personal Information We Collect**

“Personal Information” is information that identifies you as an individual, such as:

  * Name
  * Postal address (including billing and shipping addresses)
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Organization and job title or function
  * Login ID, PIN or other Password for access to certain content on the Site
  * Support Data, which we collect when you submit a support request or run an automated troubleshooter, including : information about hardware, software, and other details related to the support incident, such as: contact or authentication information, chat session personalization, information about the condition of the computer and the application when the issue occurred and during diagnostics, system and registry data about software installations and hardware configurations, and error-tracking files.

We may merge Personal Information collected through the Site with Personal Information that we collect about you offline, such as business contact information that we receive in connection with sales presentations, your emails to us or your purchases from us, information gathered when you attend a trade show, seminar or other business event, or information provided by your employer if your company enrolls you in a training event. Where required under the applicable law, we will obtain your consent in doing so. All such merged Personal Information will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We use third-party payment services (“Payment Service”) to collect payments for purchases made through the Site. If you wish to make a payment through the Site, you will be directed to a webpage that is hosted by the Payment Service (or the Payment Service’s service providers) and not by Verint. Any Personal Information that you provide through the Payment Service’s web page will be collected by Payment Service and not by us, and will be subject to Payment Service’s privacy policy, rather than this Privacy Policy. EXCEPT IN JURISDICTIONS WHERE EXPRESSLY DEEMED SO, WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE OR LIABLE FOR THE USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION BY SUCH PAYMENT SERVICES.

We need to collect Personal Information in order to provide the requested Services to you.  If you do not provide the information requested, we may not be able to provide the Services. If you disclose any Personal Information relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Services, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### **How We Use Personal Information**

We may use Personal Information:

  * To respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests, such as to send you email alerts, white papers or information about our company, products and services. 
    * We will engage in this activity with your consent or where we have a legitimate interest.
  * To send you important information regarding the Site, and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies and/or other administrative information. 
    * We engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you, to comply with a legal obligation, and/or because we have a legitimate interest.
  * To complete and fulfill your purchase, for example, to have your order delivered to you, to provide you with the products and services you request, to communicate with you regarding your purchase, and to provide you with related customer service. 
    * We will engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or to comply with a legal obligation.
  * To allow you to register for or take advantage of various opportunities, such as enrolling in online and classroom training; submitting online tickets for support or other services; participating in forums, blogs or other interactive features; or applying for your organization to become a Verint partner. 
    * We use this information to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or because we have a legitimate interest.
  * To send you marketing communications that we believe may be of interest to you. 
    * We will engage in this activity with your consent or where we have a legitimate interest.
  * To allow you to provide feedback in a customer satisfaction survey or for market research purposes. 
    * We will engage in this activity with your consent or where we have a legitimate interest.
  * To personalize your experience on the Site by presenting products and offers tailored to you. 
    * We will provide personalized services either with your consent or because we have a legitimate interest.
  * To administer and develop our business relationship with you and the organization you represent, if you represent one of our customers, business partners, or prospective customers or partners.
  * For our business purposes, such as data analysis, providing services requested by you, audits, for fraud and security monitoring purposes (for example, to detect and prevent cyberattacks or attempts to commit identity theft), developing new products, enhancing our website, improving our services, identifying usage trends and determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns. 
    * We engage in these activities to manage our contractual relationship with you, to comply with a legal obligation, and/or because we have a legitimate interest.
  * To provide you with support services through phone, email, or online chat. We may use Remote Access (RA), with your consent, to temporarily navigate your desktop. Phone conversations, online chat sessions, or RA sessions with support professionals may be recorded and/or monitored. For RA, you may also access the recording after your session. For Online Chat or RA, you may end a session at any time of your choosing. We also use Personal Information, including Support Data to help resolve your support incident and for training purposes. 
    * We engage in this activity with your consent, to manage our contractual relationship with you, and/or where we have a legitimate interest.
  * Aggregating and/or anonymizing Personal Information. We may aggregate and/or anonymize Personal Information so that it will no longer be considered Personal Information. We do so to generate other data for our use, which we may use and disclose for any purpose.

### **How Personal Information is Disclosed**

Your Personal Information may be disclosed:

  * To our Affiliates for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Verint Systems Inc. is the party responsible for the management of the jointly-used Personal Information.
  * To our third-party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, infrastructure provision, IT services, customer service, email delivery services, credit card processing, auditing services and other similar services to enable them to provide services.
  * To business partners, if you choose to purchase products and services from us that include or require products and services of our business partners (such as integration services), to enable them to provide the applicable products and services. EXCEPT IN JURISDICTIONS WHERE EXPRESSLY DEEMED SO, WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE OR LIABLE FOR THE USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION BY SUCH BUSINESS PARTNERS.
  * To identify you to anyone to whom you send messages through the Site.
  * To third-party distributors that we ask to follow-up on requests from you.
  * By you, on message boards, chat, profile pages and blogs, and other services to which you are able to post information and materials. Please note that any information you post or disclose through these services will become public information and may be available to visitors to the Site and to the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your Personal Information, or any other information, on the Site.
  * To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
  * Where required under the applicable law, we will obtain your consent in disclosing your Personal Information.

We also use and disclose Personal Information, As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our Affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our Affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

## **Other Information**

### **Other Information We Collect**

“Other Information” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual, such as:

  * Browser information
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
  * Demographic information and other information provided by you
  * Aggregated information that no longer reveals your specific identity

**How We Collect Other Information**

We and our third party service providers may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * Through your browser: Certain information is collected by most browsers, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system version and Internet browser type and version. We use this information to help ensure that our Site functions properly.
  * Using cookies and web beacons: Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.verint.com/our-company/legal-documents/cookies-overview/), which explains how we use cookies.
  * Usage data: We may use statistical data, analytics, trends and usage information derived from your use of services (“usage data”) through pixel tags and other similar technologies. Usage data includes, for example, aggregated quantitative information about active users, activity, topics, and groups. Some ways we use the usage data include operating, improving and personalizing the services and our offerings, as well as other Verint products and services.
  * IP Address: Your “IP Address” is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP Address is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user visits the Site, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. Collecting IP Addresses is standard practice on the Internet and is done automatically by many websites. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating Site usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the Site.
  * From you: Information such as your location, as well as other information, such as your preferred means of communication or areas of interest, is collected when you voluntarily provide this information. Unless combined with Personal Information, this information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site.
  * By aggregating information: Aggregated Personal Information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site. (For example, we may use aggregated Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code.)

### **How We Use and Disclose Other Information**

Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then, in addition to the uses listed in the “How We Collect Other Information” section above, we may use and disclose Other Information for all the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information.

In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information (such as combining your name with your geographical location). If we combine any Other Information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information as long as it is combined.

### **Third Party Advertising**

Data Collected in Connection with Ad Serving and Targeting. Our goal at Verint is to provide you with ads that are relevant to you. We use the services of reputable third parties to provide us with data collection, reporting, ad response measurement, and site analytics, as well as to assist with the delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may view, edit or set their own cookies. We, our third-party service providers, advertisers, advertising networks and platforms, agencies and/or partners may also place web beacons for these third parties. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this privacy statement.

Often our ads are based on the content of pages you are viewing, but we also provide ads tailored to your interests. Our hope is that by presenting ads tailored to your interests, we will enhance your experience across Verint’s websites.

For example, if you often visit content on the Verint network about Workforce Optimization (WFO), we or our service providers may use “web beacons” to infer your possible interest in WFO and may deliver an ad to you related to that interest when you are on the Site or on a third-party site. It’s important to understand that these technologies use anonymous identifiers within the “cookies” stored in your browser. We offer you choices with regard to interest-based ads. To learn more about interest-based ads and the choices available to you, please visit our [AdChoices page](https://www.verint.com/our-company/legal-documents/ad-choices/).

Verint’s Adherence to Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. Verint adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising of the Digital Advertising Alliance. To learn more about the Principles and your choices when it comes to the use of online behavioral advertising data by advertisers and ad servers across the Internet, visit http://optout.aboutads.info/#/ and <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/> .

### **Third Party Sites**

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site to which this Site contains a link. The inclusion of a link on the Site does not imply endorsement of the linked site by us or by our Affiliates.

### **Security**

We use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information under our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or data storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us in accordance with the “Contacting Us” section below.

### **Choices and Access**

Your choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information

We give you many choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information for marketing purposes. You may opt-out from the following (and in jurisdictions where prior affirmative consent is required, we shall collect such consent from you in order for you to allow us to do the following):

  * Receiving electronic communications from us: If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from us on a go-forward basis, you may opt-out by following the instructions contained in the email or by contacting us at [opt-out@verint.com](mailto:opt-out@verint.com)
  * Our sharing of your Personal Information with Affiliates for their marketing purposes: If you would prefer that we do not share your Personal Information on a go-forward basis with our Affiliates for their marketing purposes, you may opt-out of this sharing by contacting us at [opt-out@verint.com](mailto:opt-out@verint.com)
  * Our sharing of your Personal Information with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes: If you would prefer that we do not share your Personal Information on a go-forward basis with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes, you may opt-out of this sharing by contacting us at [opt-out@verint.com](mailto:opt-out@verint.com)

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please also note that if you do opt-out of receiving marketing-related messages from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, and you cannot opt-out from receiving administrative messages.

### **How to access, change or suppress your Personal Information**

If you would like to request to review, correct, update, suppress, restrict or delete or otherwise limit our use of your Personal Information that has been previously provided to us, object to the processing of Personal Information, or if you would like to request to receive an electronic copy of your Personal Information for purposes of transmitting it to another company (to the extent this right to data portability is provided to you by applicable law) you may contact us at [privacy@verint.com](mailto:privacy@verint.com) or at the addresses listed below in “Contacting Us”.  We will respond to your request consistent with applicable law.

In your request, please make clear what information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Information suppressed from our database or otherwise, and let us know which of the above limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Information. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

### **Retention Period**

We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law.

The criteria used to determine our retention periods include:

  * The length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you and provide the Services to you (for example, for as long as you have an account with us or keep using the Services);
  * Whether there is a legal obligation to which we are subject (for example, certain laws require us to keep records of your transactions for a certain period of time before we can delete them); or
  * Whether retention is advisable in light of our legal position (such as in regard to applicable statutes of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations).

### **Use** **of site by** **Minors**

The Site is not directed to individuals under the age of eighteen (18), and we request that these individuals do not provide Personal Information through the Site.

### **Cross-Border Transfer**

Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using our Site, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence or the country where the Personal Information is collected, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than in your country.  In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other countries may be entitled to access your Personal Information

We will transfer your data in accordance with applicable law when it is transferred outside your country of residence or country from where your Personal Information is collected.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION REGARDING TRANSFERS FROM THE EEA: Some of the non-EEA countries are recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection according to EEA standards (the full list of these countries is available here <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en>

For transfers from the EEA to countries not considered adequate by the European Commission, we have put in place adequate measures, such as standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission to protect your Personal Information. You may obtain a copy of these measures by following this link <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en>

### **Sensitive Information**

We do not collect any sensitive Personal Information (e.g., information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership).  We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any such sensitive Personal Information to us.

### **Information** **we handle as a service provider**

In the course of providing goods and services to our customers, Verint may receive information in the form of text, sound, software or image files from our customers and distributors about their own customers (“Customer Information”). Verint makes no claim of ownership to Customer Information. Our customers may collect Personal Information, and at their request, we may host that data as part of service offerings on our platform. Verint acts only in accordance with our customers’ or distributors’ instructions and applicable law with respect to such information, and its collection, use and disclosure is governed by the privacy policy and practices of the customer or distributor concerned and not by this Privacy Policy. You should review the customer’s privacy policy or contact the customer directly to understand how they will use the data you submit to them.

### **Compliance with Relevant Laws, Ordinances, and Guidelines**

When handling Personal Information, we shall comply with applicable laws and ordinances, and guidelines.

## **Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy. Please take a look at the “LAST UPDATED” legend at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Your use of the Site following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.

## **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at privacy@verint.com, or write to the following address:

Verint Systems Inc.

Attn: Legal Department/Privacy Policy

175 Broadhollow Rd, Ste 100

Melville, NY 11747

Please note that email communications are not always secure, so please do not include credit card information or sensitive information in your emails to us.

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION REGARDING THE EEA**

You may also:

  * Contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO) at [privacy@verint.com](mailto:privacy@verint.com).
  * Lodge a complaint with a data protection authority for your country or region or where an alleged infringement of applicable data protection law occurs. A list of data protection authorities is available at [http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080](https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/GVKtCmZM8ki2Bq0BH312ig). ** **
